大家要知道  我们并不是在教你如何
Now, it's important to remember that we're not here to teach you how to
做一个天气应用
build a weather app.
不是在教你我们做这个程序所用到的API
It's not even to teach you all the Android
APIs that we use to build it.
而是在锻炼你的大脑  让你像一个移动应用开发者一样思考
It's really about retraining your brain to start thinking like a mobile developer,
思考方式真的很重要  因为我们在课程结束的时候会要求你自己
which is really important, because at the end of this course we're gonna ask you to
做一个项目
build your own final project.
[NOISE].
这里我希望你已经理会面向对象编程的思想
We're expecting you to already be familiar with object-oriented programming, and
并且有Java等类似语言基础
to have experience with Java or a similar language.
就我个人而言  我在做了几年的Delphi和C＃之后转做Android开发
Personally, I got started with Android after years of Delphi and C# development.
作为工程师  我们一般都会把当前的经验应用到一门新的开发语言
As engineers, we're trained to map our experiences in one language or
或者SDK
SDK into new ones.
找出他们之间相似的模式可以让我们以最快的速度入门
Looking for patterns and shortcuts we can get up to speed as quickly as possible.
但是移动开发者  尤其是Android开发者
But mobile, and Android in particular,
从本质上说跟普通开发者还是有不同的  也即是说一些既定的经验
have some fundamental differences that mean some of our experience and
和直觉极有可能让你变成一个不称职的移动开发者
intuition will actually make us worse mobile engineers.
我们习惯性的把智能手机认为是缩小版的电脑
We like to think of Smartphones as computers that fit into our pockets.
从某种意义上这本无异议  但是电脑是来自90年代的东东
In a way that's true, but the computers from the 90s,
就像20年前我用的这个Powerhouse一样
like this Powerhouse I was using nearly 20 years ago.
它网速超级慢  CPU处理速度也慢
With limited internet connectivity, low speed CPUs, and
内存也小的可怜  除此之外  这些东西全部需要电源供电
limited RAM, on top of which, they're all running on batteries.
在我们的课程里
As we go through the course,
我们将在移动开发上重新面临这些问题
I'll be returning to each of these key mobile challenges.
你在桌面环境开发  服务器端
Looking for places where you're experienced on desktop or
或者其他移动平台上的开发经验很可能把你带到坑口去
server, or even other mobile platforms might lead you in the wrong direction.
同样的  我会跟你分享一些早期Android系统的故事
I will also be back to tell you some stories from the early days of Android.
一些描述Android系统是如何迭代更新的故事
Stories that describe how the Android platform has evolved.
我在的这个地方  就是最具代表性的
And nowhere is that more readily apparent than here,
Android Lawn雕塑园
at the Android Lawn sculpture garden.
在这个Android的中心  我邀请你加入我们的课程  在课程结束的时候
Join me here, at the very heart of Android, at the end of this lesson,
就能知道这些雕塑的代表着什么
to find out how this sculpture garden of tasty treats,
也可以从中知道Android的历史
also tell us the story of Android's history.
现在开始  我们回到做天气应用的话题
For now, let's get back to building that weather app.
我们邀请Dan来开讲
So, we'll cross to Dan, to take a look at some mocks.